I am from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky, and
Я из Украины город Хмельницкий А вы с
what city of Russia, the city of Ryazan,
какого города России город Рязань Россия
are you from
вы по национальности то эрзя русский Кто
?  this is the
Ну на этой территории жили когда там это
most
самое
historically most likely not, well, the
исторически скорее всего не ну
aesthetic tribes of Elsa lived there
эстетические там племена Эльзы жили там
Mordva,
Мордва
well, and when when your ancestors came
ну причем когда когда ваши предки пришли
to the territory of Ryazan, where are yours from where did they
на территорию Рязани вот ваши откуда они
come
пришли мне интересно
from?  I’m asking
смотрите Я у людей из России спрашиваю
today how do you feel about the future
сегодня как вы относитесь к будущим
color revolutions in Russia and the disintegration of
цветным революциям в России и распаду
Russia into independent states is
России на независимые государства плохо
bad Why
А почему
Well, because Russia is a single country
Ну потому что Россия это единая страна
Well, why judge Why
Ну а зачем судить Зачем бурятом
Buryats should be Chechens Russians in one country Buryats should live independent Buryatia
буряты должны независимой Бурятии жить
Chechens in Chechnya No, I’m with  you why that's
чеченцы в Чечне Нет я с вами почему вот
interesting why But remember the parable about the
интересно почему Но помните притчу про
broom about the broom So there are
веник про веник Так что там по
them separately  they broke but together they couldn’t
отдельности их ломали а вместе не смогли
broken yes Well, why are you Buryats or
сломана да Ну а зачем бурятом вы или
Chechens
чеченцам вы
But we live together and live well so they
Но вместе живем и неплохо живем так
can and without you
могут и без вас
they will be worse Why
они будут хуже Почему
Because you broke off in the ass,
Потому что откололись вы попали в жопу
look, for example, as a Tatar Bashkir, it’s better to
смотрите например татаром башкиром лучше
be friends with Turkey than with Russia
дружить Турции чем с России
for the Tatars here  Kazakhs there are Turks, they are more
для татар вот казахи там турки они более
related nationalities
родственные народности
Well, that's how the symbiosis was formed, here's the
Ну вот как вот симбиоз образовался вот
symbiosis That's exactly useful Well, remember biology,
симбиоз Вот именно полезные Ну биологии
I remember
помните помню
Well, Sim dog climbed the cohabitation of two
Ну вот Сим пёс полез сожительство двух
plants
растений
symbiosis suggests that several
симбиоз предполагает то что несколько
living organisms somehow interact
живых организмов как-то взаимодействуют
and bring
и привносят
yes And here's what You bring  the Buryats benefit the
да А вот чем Вот вы приносите пользу там
Tatars there, and here you are,
бурятом татарам и вот конкретно вы
but firstly they live in a big country,
но они во-первых живут большой стране
what kind of subsidies they receive There they
они какие дотации получают Там они там
get even there they give us something there,
получает еще чет они что-то дают нам там
well, what subsidies do you specifically
ну что какие дотации вы конкретно
pay and where do you pay subsidies from,
платить и откуда вы платите дотации
for example, Tatars or Bashkirs  of which
например татарами или башкиром у которых
there is oil
есть нефть
Well, in Russia there are much more of you here in
Ну в России намного больше вот вас вот в
Ryazan You have oil in the first place
Рязани У вас есть нефть во-первых
logistics is also logistics
логистика тоже логистика
l  logistics, that is, without you, without you,
логистика то есть без вас без вас
they won’t be able to do logistics Yes, there are
логистику не смогут сделать Да там
Tatars, for example,
татары например
They wo
Они через Казахстан что-то там
n’t be able to export something through Kazakhstan Yes,
экспортировать не смогу Да вот Ну
well, first of all, they will have a border Orenburg
во-первых у них граница будет Оренбург
Orenburg will be Kazakhstan
Оренбург будет Казахстаном
Straight in general was Kazakhstan
Прям вообще был Казахстаном был
Orenburg was the first capital of Kazakhstan then
Оренбург первая столица Казахстана потом
just  they took it separated There they live on the map from above,
просто взяли отделили Там сверху живут
the Turkic
на карте тюркский
half a year ago was, let’s say, in
полгода назад был вот допустим в этой
this one how positive people are
вот насколько вот позитивный народ
positively But what are you specifically What
позитивно А вот что вы вот конкретно Вот
are you called by the way Andrey
вы как вас зовут кстати вот мне Андрей
what exactly do you give Vadim useful in this
что вы конкретно Вадим даете в этой
common country Bashkir Tatar
общей стране полезного башкиром татаром
Chuvash
чувашем
Well  I just can, specifically for the
Ну я просто могу вот вы конкретно для
Tatars, what benefits does this symbiosis bring
татар какую пользу приносит в этом
in the first place, tartan But at least in
во-первых тартане Но по крайней мере в
Naberezhnye Chelny and Kazan,
Набережных Челнах и в Казани
people simply don’t think of themselves without Russia
люди просто себя без России не мыслят Ну
Well, for example, they will understand what you can
вот а вот например они поймут что можно
think.  in one
мыслить Вот и придумают вот есть в один
of Ryazan And what gives us in one of
из Рязани А что нам дает в один из
Ryazan here we are in one of Ryazan we
Рязани вот мы в один из Рязани у нас
pump oil from Bashkortostan And what
выкачивать нефть из Башкортостана А что
do we get  No
нам дает
Well, first of all, I just know that they get the
Ну во-первых я просто знать так достают
embankment. There is a
набережной человек есть завод КАМАЗ
KAMAZ plant. They heard such.
такой слышали такой слышал да Камский
look, for example, we buy an iPhone
смотрите например вот мы покупаем iPhone
from the Americans that kind of money, but the lower ones
у американцев такие деньги но нижние
are obliged to live in our country, really No,
обязаны жить у нас стране правда Нет
look
смотрите
at yours, these Americans KAMAZ
в ваш вот эти вот американцы Камазы
will buy
будут покупать
you need Well
нужно Ну
, the KAMAZ plant and you are their non-city forming
а завод КАМАЗ и ты их неграда образующие
enterprises,
предприятия
so you look at what
так вот смотрите Вы в Рязани на чем
you will be in Ryazan  Tatars will have to drive all night to
будете ездить всю ночь придется татар
buy Kamaz True Well, let's say I bought
купить Камаз Правда Ну допустим я купил
buy Kamaz we I need for
купите Камаз мы Мне нужны для
Kamaz spare parts Yes buy spare
камазапчасти Да купить у них запчасти
parts from them bought me a spare part they have money
купил мне запчасть у них есть деньги у
they can buy such things there I
них они могут такие купить там себе не
don’t know there well clothes there products
знаю там ну одежду там продукты еще
something else  in short, what else do you see exactly what
что-то короче что смотри еще что
you give to the Tatars Bashkirs
конкретно вы даете татарам башкиром
Chechens
чеченцам
you specifically Vadim
вы конкретно Вадим
you are like a Russian I consume them ska  so
вы как русский я потребляя их скажем так
I’m a consumer of their product So you are
я потребитель ихний продукт Так вы
consumers of Chinese products given
потребители китайской продукции данного
for some reason China is not part of
почему-то Китай не входит в состав
Russia of independent states Why
России независимых государств Почему
can China sell goods to you Why is
Китай вам может продавать товар Почему
it that the Tatars of Bashkiria themselves will not be able
так сама Башкирии татары не смогут
to sell so you yourself will consume
продавать так сам будете потреблять
sit on the couch consume
сидеть на диване потреблять
but we live in one  country, you understand that
но мы живем в одной стране понимаете что
we will have an economy, we have a single
у нас будет экономика у нас единая
economy So that's exactly what turns out
Экономика Так вот именно что получается
you are not a symbiosis And parasitism, so it
вас не симбиоз А паразитизм так
turns out that you give out if it’s
получается вы что выдает если это себе
what you Kamaz do what you make of
что вы Камаз делать из чего вы делаете
Bashkiria you caught in Ryazan
есть Башкирия вы в Рязань
yes
ты поймал да
look here for example I look  on your
смотрите вот например я смотрю на ваши
teeth if you have such an economic
зубы если у вас так экономическое все
interaction, why do you have
взаимодействие почему вот у вас есть
problems Russians with
проблемы у Россиян со стоматологом
our dentist have no money
нашего нет денег
really everyone is afraid of everyone who is not land
реально все боятся все кого не сушу
Russians everyone is afraid but the Americans are not
русских все боятся но американцы не
afraid because the Americans
боятся потому что у американцев
have such technologies that it can be done without
технологии есть такие что можно это не
pain
больно сделать
There is also here But expensive
Здесь тоже есть Но дорого
Yes no In
Да нет
short, in general, you think that you
короче в общем вы считаете так что вы
live in symbiosis  but you can’t specifically
живете в симбиозе но вы конкретно не
say what you give the
можете сказать что вы даете тогда
Bashkirs to the Tatars useful
башкиром татарам полезного
then that they are not only for us to
то что они нам не только вот вы
pump out their resources, so from whom
выкачивать их не ресурсы так с кого
Bashkortostan Bashneft, for example, And so
Башкортостан Башнефть например И так
on, it’s all like there is how much resource extraction is there,
дальше это все типа там сколько добычи
and Bashkortostan for some reason
ресурсов а Башкортостан почему-то
is considered a subsidized region,
дотационный регион считается
but  you understand, I’m coming back so
но понимаете вот возвращаюсь давайте так
that
чтобы
Tell me what you can give them so that I
Скажите что вы можете им дать чтобы я
understand and run further that you give
понял и побегу дальше что вы даете
everything everything The Lord of the world is light heat and
все все Властелин мир свет тепло и
electricity I don’t know it’s warm there heat
электричество Я не знаю там тепло тепло
is only when you lie down
у вас там только когда Лежите лежним так
so you give off heat That’s just it
вот вы тепло выделяете Вот это только
you give warmth so we must
тепло даете так вот мы должны
pedal this topic the topic of the collapse of
педалировать эту тему тему распада
Russia into independent states Why
России на независимые государства Почему
is this important A lot of people in Russia are
Это важно Очень много людей в России
enslaved peoples they don’t realize they are
порабощенных народов они не осознают им
told that Bashkortostan is a
говорят что там Башкортостан
subsidized region there that if they are
дотационный регион что если они делятся
divided they don’t have enough of them that’s how to deceive
у них не хватает вот как их Обманывать
this subsidized region  because with the
это дотационный регион потому что с
Federal budget and they add
Федеральным бюджета и еще добавляют
money, but why Because there are local
денег а почему Потому что есть местные
budgets  Yes, there are local taxes, there are federal taxes, it
бюджеты Да есть местные налоги есть
turns out that the state
федеральные получается государство
takes a bunch of
забирает федеральными налогами кучу
dough
бабла
with federal taxes and fills it with local taxes, and now
местными налогами наполняют и теперь
they say, look
говорят вот смотрите
Damn, how is it in Russian, your expenses of
Блин как это по-русски он ваши расходы
your local
ваших местных
local budget are not enough, so we
местного бюджета не хватает поэтому мы
add subsidies to you from the state treasury
вам из государственной казны добавляем
But this money goes to the State
дотацию Но эти деньги в Государственную
treasury  where did they get from the fact that they were taken
казну откуда попали из того что их взяли
through the federal tax through
через федеральный налог через
federal taxes, that is, in the total amount,
федеральные налоги то есть в общей сумме
they conditionally took away X money from the same Bashkords there
у башкордов тех же отобрали условно там
and returned 50 percent of
X денег а вернули там 50 процентов от
X there, and everyone says that they also call it a
икса Вот и все говорят вот еще называют
subsidized region, so people
дотационным регионом поэтому люди
learn to count their resources to count
научитесь считать свои ресурсы считать
then how
то как
Moscow
Москва
gives people can’t name it, it can
даешь людям не может назвать он может
name it because nothing because
назвать потому что ничего потому что
symbiosis implies that every
симбиоз подразумевает то что каждый
living organism gives something useful,
живой организм что-то отдает полезное
this is parasitism
это паразитизм